http://www.liverpoolfc.com/legal/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
WEBSITE PRIVACY NOTICE
This Privacy Notice explains in detail the types of personal data we may collect about you when you interact with us. It also explains how we’ll store and handle that data, and keep it safe.
There’s a lot of information here, but we want you to be fully informed about your rights, and how Liverpool Football Club uses your data; for example, we will explain how we analyse and combine all the data we hold about you to ensure communications are personalised and relevant.
We hope the following sections will answer any questions you have but if not, please do get in touch with us.
Summary of how we use your data
Our website and app are designed to allow fans of Liverpool Football Club ("LFC", "we" or "us") to interact with the club. We use your personal data in various ways to facilitate this.
LFC's use of your personal data allows us to provide products, tickets and services that you have purchased, to communicate with our fans, to provide you with information about us and about our products, services and events and may also include, where we are allowed to do so, contacting you about products and services and events that we think you'll be interested in.
Our privacy notice describes how LFC will make use of your personal information when you visit our website or app, when we communicate with you and when you buy tickets or products from us:
What information we collect and why;
Our use of data analytics;
The legal basis on which we process your information;
Who we share your personal information with, where and when;
Your rights over your personal information;
How you can get in contact with us to discuss your personal information;
How to opt-out of direct marketing;
Who the data controller over your personal information is; and
How long we will keep your personal information.
Where we transfer your data internationally we make sure that it is protected according to the standards required by applicable law.
You also have various rights over your personal data including a right to object to some of the processing of your personal data that LFC carries out.
The website and our app may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy notices. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.
What information do we collect and why?
We collect and process personal data about you when you register to use this or our other websites or our app or purchase or express an interest in receiving products or services from us or subscribing to our communications.  This includes:
Your contact details including your name, postal and email address and telephone number.
To contact you in order for us to manage, administer and provide our products and services to you.
To respond to any correspondence and service-related enquiries you send to us in respect of our products or services.
To provide you with relevant information such as operational updates (including access information, ticket collection information and fixture changes) relating to match days and other events.
We will use this information to market products and services to you where you have consented to this.
We will also use this information to market LFC products and services to you (including via electronic means) and to inform you about LFC news, competitions, events and other information, to the extent you have not opted-out and to the extent such marketing relates to a product and/or service you have previously ordered or purchased or to a product or service you are communicating with us or have expressed an interest in.
We may use this information to collect payment of debts from you, for example where payments for hospitality are overdue.
We may receive this information from the Premier League rather than collecting it directly from you ourselves, but usually only where you have opted-in (e.g. on the Premier League website) to receiving information from us.
We may also receive this information from licensees of our brand (e.g. third party apps, games and retail outlets) where you have opted-in with that licensee for your information being shared with us.
To communicate any updates to you including any changes to our services, the terms and conditions of any services which we have provided to you, any changes to this Privacy Notice and to our websites.
To invite you to give feedback and/or take part in market research or surveys to assist us with improving fan experiences and our products and services.
Identity details including your title, name, date of birth, gender, user name, social media handles or other similar identifier.
To register you as a fan, to establish your identity and to ensure that we are corresponding with and providing products and services to the correct person.
To enable your participation in a prize draw or competition which you have entered.
To market products / services to you where you have consented to this. We will also use this information to market LFC products and services to you (including via electronic means) and to inform you about LFC news, competitions, events and other information, to the extent you have not opted-out and to the extent such marketing relates to a product and/or service you have previously ordered or purchased or to a product or service you are communicating with us or have expressed an interest in.
We may use this information to collect payment of debts from you, for example where payments for hospitality are overdue.
We may receive this information from the Premier League rather than collecting it directly from you ourselves, but only where you have opted-in (e.g. on the Premier League website) to receiving information from us.
We may also receive this information from licensees of our brand (e.g. third party apps, games and retail outlets) where you have opted-in with that licensee for your information being shared with us.
We only collect information about your gender for statistical purposes and to personalise the products and services we offer to you.
Financial information including bank account and payment card details.
Your payment card details may be collected via our website or app. This information is used solely for billing purposes by our PCI-DSS certified payment services provider. Your payment card information is encrypted and transmitted to our payment services provider securely via HTTPS. Your payment card details are never stored on our systems, and no one at LFC can access them. A limited selection of our staff can access your payment card's expiration date to ensure your payment information remains valid.
We may collect your bank account details to process any subscriptions (e.g. TV subscriptions, regular season ticket payments) you enter into with us.
Details of payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us including any feedback.
To allow us to provide you with any products or services you have purchased from us.
To administer any refunds that we provide to you.
To enable you to track your payments history through your account.
To establish whether other products / services that we may wish to contact you about (where we are entitled to do so) are relevant.
To respond to comments / complaints you or others may send to us.
To improve and protect our products, platforms, content, services and websites.
To check your eligibility for tickets and other events which you wish to attend.
Your preferences in receiving marketing communications from us and any third parties (including any consents you have given us) and confirmation of whether or not we should contact you.
To make sure that we only send marketing information to you where we are entitled to do so.
We receive a 'yes' or 'no' answer at our request from the Telephone Preference Service and as a result of mortality and gambling/betting/financial screening as an indication of whether we should contact you for marketing purposes.
Your official supporters' club membership status.
We receive a 'yes' or 'no' answer at our request from the official supporters' club as to whether you are a member.
This assists with ticketing and providing benefits to members.
Your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
We will use this information to show you information that is relevant to you including your account information and history to allow you to administer your account.
We also use some of this information for analytics purposes, which are described in more detail below under 'Our use of data analytics'.
Technical data about your access to and use of the website and app.
This is likely to include IP address (from which we may infer your country of location), the type of device you are using, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the device you use to access our website or app and information about whether you open our communications, which content you have viewed and other page interaction information.
This is primarily to help us better understand how our fans use our digital platforms to enable us to create better content and more relevant communications.  For more information on this, please see our Cookies Policy.
As part of the Champions Trophy Experience within the Official App, 'Champions Presented by Standard Charted’ we use Truedepth API to access the Front facing camera on iOS devices. The only use of this information is to provide valuable user features. None of the information collected by the TrueDepth API ever leaves the user's device. We do not share information around the TrueDepth API with third parties and we do not store or process in any other way the data which we access and use via TrueDepth API. As part of this feature in the Official LFC App a user can opt to use the function to place stickers on their face and can opt to save photographs of themselves. LFC do not store any of this face data within the App or on a server.
Information relating to any access, disability and/or dietary requirements you may have.
We will generally only request this information where it is needed for ticketing or hospitality purposes, for example where you have bought a ticket to an event so that we can make sure there are suitable accessibility arrangements in place.
Information required by law.
This may include, for example, where we need parental consent to provide online services to children under 13 (however, most of our websites are not designed for children under 13) or in response to requests by government or law enforcement authorities conducting an investigation.
Copies of identity documents where you are a season ticket holder (in which case we may collect details including your place of birth and residential address) which may include a photograph.
Where you are a season ticket holder, we may take copies of your identity documents in order to verify your identity.
We will only keep copies of your identity documents for as long as it takes us to verify your identity and will then securely delete those copies.
We use software that analyses the copies of identity documents that you provide to us which may automatically make a decision about your identity. However, where an automatic decision of this kind is made, you will always have the opportunity to challenge it if you disagree with the decision made.
We will not use the copies we take of your identity documents for any other purpose.
We may take a photograph of you to confirm your identity during the Season Ticket Amnesty process. This will be deleted once the amnesty has been completed and will not be stored by LFC for longer than this.
Please note that we may use any of the data described above to prevent, investigate and/or report fraud, terrorism, misrepresentation, security incidents or crime (including but not limited to ticketing offences), in accordance with applicable law.
____________________________________________________________________________________
Our use of data analytics
We evaluate, categorise and profile personal data to help us tailor materials, services and communications on our platforms and on third party platforms such as social media. This also helps prevent unwanted communications from filling up your inbox. This also helps us understand and provide a better experience to our fans, improve and protect our organisation and carry out research connected to our aims.
Internal research and analysis: We carry out research and analysis on our supporters, members and volunteers, to determine the success of campaigns and appeals, better understand behaviour and responses and identify patterns and trends. This helps inform our approach and make LFC a stronger and more effective organisation. Understanding our fans, their interests and what they care about also helps us provide a better experience.
Analysis and grouping: We analyse the data we collect about fans to identify common characteristics and preferences. We do this by assessing various types of information including behaviour, for example, previous activity or demographic information, such as age or location. This allows us to ensure you receive the communications, products and information which are most important to you.
Profiling to help us understand our fans: We profile fans on the basis of various criteria including their interests, general geographic location, website/app activity and socioeconomic and age groups. We also use aggregated, anonymised lifestyle data obtained from third parties to supplement our profiles. This information helps us to ensure communications are relevant and timely and to offer new products and services that may be of interest to our fans.
Several of these analytics activities rely on the use of cookies. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies.  If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our website or platforms may become inaccessible or not function properly.  For more information about the cookies we use, please see our Cookies Policy.
____________________________________________________________________________________
Legal basis for processing personal data
Our legal basis for collecting and using your personal data will depend on the personal data concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.
If we ask you to provide personal data to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you or with your explicit consent, we can provide details of this to you on request. We will advise you at the time whether the provision of your personal data is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal data).
If we collect and use your personal data in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), you may request that we provide with you information about what those legitimate interests are by contacting us using the details at 'How do I get in touch with you?' below.
____________________________________________________________________________________
Who will we share this data with, where and when?
Data will also be shared with third party service providers, who will process it on behalf of LFC for the purposes identified above.  Such third parties include providers of social media platforms and search engines, providers of services to the club such as website hosting, app developers, software providers, maintenance providers, payment providers, identity verification providers, video streaming companies, mailing companies and marketing services,
Personal data may be shared with government authorities and/or law enforcement officials if required for the purposes above, if mandated by law or if required for the legal protection of our legitimate interests in compliance with applicable laws.
We will only share your data with a third party for the purpose of them directly marketing to you where you have consented to such data sharing (for example, when entering into a specific competition for which we have partnered with that third party).
We may need to store or transfer your personal information to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA), some of which do not protect privacy rights as extensively as in the United Kingdom. However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Notice. Further details of these safeguards can be provided for your review on request by contracting our Data Protection Officer using the contact information set out under the heading ‘How do I get in touch with you or your data protection officer?’ below.
In the event that the business is sold or integrated with another business, your details will be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser’s adviser and will be passed to the new owners of the business.
____________________________________________________________________________________
What rights do I have?
You have the right to ask us for a copy of your personal data; to correct, delete or restrict (stop any active) processing of your personal data; and to obtain the personal data you provide to us for a contract or with your consent in a structured, machine readable format.
In addition, you can object to the processing of your personal data in some circumstances (in particular, where we don’t have to process the data to meet a contractual or other legal requirement, or where we are using the data for direct marketing).
Wherever we rely on your consent, you will always be able to withdraw that consent, although we may have other legal grounds for processing your data for other purposes, such as those set out above. In some cases, we are able to send you direct marketing without your consent, where we rely on our legitimate interests.  You have an absolute right to opt-out of direct marketing, or profiling we carry out for direct marketing, at any time. You can do this by following the instructions in the communication where this is an electronic message, or by contacting us using the details set out below:
These rights may be limited, for example if fulfilling your request would reveal personal data about another person, or if you ask us to delete information which we are required by law to keep or have compelling legitimate interests in keeping.
To exercise any of these rights, you can get in touch with us or our data protection officer using the details set out below. If you have unresolved concerns, you have the right to complain to an EU data protection authority where you live, work or where you believe a breach may have occurred. This likely to be the Information Commissioner’s Office in the UK.
____________________________________________________________________________________
How do I get in touch with you or your data protection officer?
We hope that we can satisfy queries you may have about the way we process your data. You can get in touch with LFC's Data Protection Officer if you have any concerns or queries about how we process your data at DPO@liverpoolfc.com or by writing to the following address:
FAO: Data Protection Officer
The Liverpool Football Club and Athletic Grounds Limited
10th Floor
20 Chapel Street
Liverpool
L3 9AG
____________________________________________________________________________________
How do I opt-out of direct marketing?
There are several ways you can stop direct marketing communications from us:
click the 'unsubscribe' link in any email marketing communications which we send you and make changes in our preference centre
if you have any account registration on our website or any of our product or service areas, log-in to the 'My LFC' or 'My Account' area and update or change your preferences; or
contact our Fan Experience team using our Contact Us page.
Please note that you may continue to receive communications for a short period after changing your preferences while all our systems are fully updated.
___________________________________________________________________________________
Which Liverpool entity is my data controller, and which affiliates might my data be shared with?
The data controller for your information is The Liverpool Football Club & Athletic Grounds Limited, except where you have consented to us sharing your data with third party partners for direct marketing purposes where the data controller will be such third party partner.
____________________________________________________________________________________
How long will you retain my data?
We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements).
When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.
